Finding Aid for the Nancy Jo Fostvedt Tice Bloom Collection of Family Photographs by Will Connell, 1933-1946 LSC.2105
UCLA Library Special Collections
Nancy Jo Fostvedt Tice Bloom Collection of Family Photographs by Will Connell
1933-1946
UCLA Library Special Collections
Bloom, Nancy Jo Fostvedt Tice
LSC.2105
1 oversize_boxes
Opal Weimer Fostvedt Tice (ca. 1900-1978) was a member of the Los Angeles art community and often a model for photographers in the group. Will Connell (1898-1961) was a self taught photographer (1920s). He opened a studio in downtown Los Angeles, exhibited in Pictorialist exhibits, and was a member of the Camera Pictorialist. In 1931, he started a 30-year teaching career at Art Center College of Design. He also worked for movie studios and magazines, did commercial photography, and was one of the first photojournalists. The collection consists of photographs or portraits of Opal Weimer Fostvedt Tice and her family taken by Will Connell. Subjects include other Fostvedt Family members, Connell Family members, and various friends.
no content
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Jo Tice Bloom, 1981.
General note
The collection contains portraits of Opal Weimer Fostvedt Tice and her family by Will Connell. Included are photographs of Cynthia Tice taken to illustrate an article in October 10, 1942 edition of The Saturday Evening Post. A letter with information about the portrait subjects is in the collection folder.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942303913606533
Biography
Opal Weimer Fostvedt Tice was born in Portland, Oregon, ca. 1900; married Willaim C. Fostvedt (1926), divorced and married Fred A. Tice (1943); was a member of the Los Angeles art community and often a model for photographers in the group; died ca. 1978.
William C. Fostvedt was born in Olso, Norway, 1902; migrated to U.S., 1907; was a banker; died in Los Angeles, 1964.
Nancy Jo Fostvedt Tice Bloom, daughter of Opal and William, was born in Los Angeles, California, 1933.
Cynthia S. Tice, daughter of Opal and William, was born in Los Angeles, California, 1937.
Will Connell was born in McPherson, Kansas, 1898; became a self taught photographer (1920s) and opened a studio in downtown Los Angeles; exhibited in Pictorialist exhibits and was a member of the Camera Pictorialist; started 30-year teaching career at Art Center College of Design (1931); closed his Los Angeles studio and did jobs for movie studios and magazines as well as commercial photography; one of the first photojournalists, he illustrated articles for Colliers and The Saturday evening post; produced 3 photography books and wrote a monthly column for U.S. Camera entitled, "Counsel by Connell"; died 1961.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of photographs or portraits of Opal Weimer Fostvedt Tice and her family taken by Will Connell. Includes photographs of Cynthia Tice taken to illustrate an article about war orphans in the October 10, 1942 issue of The Saturday evening post. Subjects include other Fostvedt Family members, Connell Family members, and various friends.
Photographers -- California -- Archives.; Photographs.; Fostvedt-Tice family; Connell, Will; Fostvedt-Tice family--Archives.
- Cabinet photographs., (Mounted, 16.5 × 11cm.) (Box 1)
  - 1. Opal Fostvedt., n.d. (Box 1)
  - 2. Opan and William Fostvedt. (Box 1)
  - 3. Margaret Hilda., 1906-1936 (Box 1)
  - 4. William Fostvedt., n.d. (Box 1)
  - 5. Will Jr. and Samantha Connell. (Box 1)
  - 6. Portrait of Connell family: Will, Grace, Will Jr., and Samantha., 1946 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Verso: "Hapy New Year 1946." Mount: "Will Connell Swell Photographer 355 No. Berendo Los Angeles."
- Unmounted photographs., 1942; (Approximately 25 × 20.5cm.) (Box 1)
  General note
  Photographs 1-6 were taken in September 1942 for an article in the Saturday Evening Post, October 10, 1942, p.20.
  - 1-5. Cynthia Fostvedt. Various poses of the little girl crying. (Box 1)
  - 6. Cynthia Fostvedt. Photograph used to illustrate article. (Box 1)
  - 7. Nancy Fostvedt., 1937; (24.7 × 19.7cm.) (Box 1)
- Saturday Evening Post., October 10, 1942 (Box 1)
  Will Connell's photographs illustrate a story on war orphans.
- Oversize photograph., (Mounted, 45.8 × 35.7, unless otherwise noted) (Box 1)
  - 1-2. Opal Fostvedt and sleeping baby Nancy., 1933; (2 copies, duplicates) (Box 1)
  - 3-4. Nancy on Opal's shoulder., 1933; (2 photographs, different views) (Box 1)
  - 5. Opal wearing necklace and holding Nancy., 1933 (Box 1)
  - 6. Opal holding Nancy in the air., 1933 (Box 1)
  - 7. William, Nancy, and Opal Fostvedt., 1933 (Box 1)
  - 8. Nancy, William, and Opal Fostvedt., 1933 (Box 1)
  - 9. Dr. Carl Fisher and Nancy., 1933 (Box 1)
  - 10-11. "To Grandma Weimer from Nancy. June 7, 1934."., ([Mat trimmed: 42 × 35.7cm., and damaged] 2 copies, duplicate) (Box 1)
  - 12. Nancy Fostvedt., 1934; (Outdoor photograph) (Box 1)
  - 13-14. Nancy, right profile., 1934 (Box 1)
  - 15. Nancy., 1934 (Box 1)
  - 16-17. Nancy smiling., 1934; (2 photographs, different views) (Box 1)
  - 18. Nancy crawling on grass., 1934 (Box 1)
  - 19. Opal, Nancy, William Fostvedt, and dog Buddy., 1934 (Box 1)
  - 20. Budd Frankenfield and Nancy., 1934 (Box 1)
  - 21. Mable Williams Frankenfield and Nancy., 1934 (Box 1)
  - 22. Nancy sitting in front of fireplace., 1934 (Box 1)
  - 21-24. "Opal"., 1936; (2 copies, duplicates, #24 untitled) (Box 1)
  - 25. "Opal Fostvedt"., 1936 (Box 1)
  - 26. "Cyndy, Opal, Nancy Fostvedt, Feb. 1, 1941". (Box 1)
  - 27. "Cyndy & Nancy Fostvedt, January 1941". (Box 1)
  - 28. "Bill". Portrait of Will Connell, Jr., 1937 (Box 1)